Chet Budhathoki

Email: okchet@gmail.com
Phone: 801-792-2850
1224 Illinois Ave
SLC, UT 84104

International Humanities Advocate - Health Education - Language Specialist

Having lived throughout Nepal, Korea & America, I have a proven work record in providing excellence within all sectors of the work environment. Using my specialized business cultural communication and management skills, I work to make a difference in the lives of others, always working toward a better tomorrow.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2018-Current: USANA Health Sciences - Quality Engineer (IT)

- As a IT Quality Engineer, my daily responsibility is to make sure we deliver the best quality products to the end user which requires:
 - Code review
 - Creating test cases
 - Executing test cases
 - Plan/attend sprint planning meeting
 - Story grooming and commitment

2016-2017: USANA Health Sciences-Compliance Auditor

Making sure USANA policies and procedures are properly implemented. Audit customers
account for AP Growth, Convention Growth, Elite Bonus Qualifier, Incentive winners, Rank
Advancement including but not limited to any and all unusual activities like sudden growth,
sudden excessive purchasing, sudden many sponsorships etc.

2016-2017: USANA Health Sciences-Regulatory Affairs Specialist

• Overview with the new product development, Ingredients/formula, marketing & health claims review, customs documentation, label creation

2015- 2016: USANA Health Sciences-International Coordinator

• Coordinate between local market to home office with regards to product launch, promotion, system related (Internal & external) issues and help organize all kinds of events.

2013-2015: USANA Health Sciences: VIP support team

Helping leaders with their business needs

- Member of Platinum PaceSetter Committee (The Platinum PaceSetter Committee researches and verifies the legitimacy of a distributor achievements i.e. rank advancement, commission earned
- **Commission Approver :** As a member of commission approver, I oversee the work done by other distributor services agents to make sure everything is accurate and legit

2010-2013 USANA Health Sciences: Distributor Services

- Health Education, Distributor Services, Order Management
- Translation & interpretation Services, Business Information, Project Management

2009-2009 Korea-Nepal Friendship Hospital: Interpreter – Bhaktapur, Nepal

• Korean/Nepalese Interpretation Services in a hospital environment.

2008-2010 ChetLand Cyber Center: Sole-Proprietor –Bhaktapur, Nepal

- Management & Daily Operations: Software/hardware operation and maintenance of about 7 internet accessed computers
- Translation, Document Services, Computer Training & Language Consultation

2001-2008 Standard Drawing Instruments: Engineering & Animation –South Korea

- Office Manager & Assistant Operations Manager: Internet Orders, Shipping & Receiving.
- Developing & Manufacturing: Animation Amateur & Drawing Instruments.

2004-2008 World's Friend(<u>club.cyworld.com/worldenglish</u>): Founder; Culture & Language Educator –South Korea

- Teaching Korean & English Language
- Community Building & Inspiring Culture Development

EDUCATION

1997-1999	Tribhuvan University , Associate Degree: Commerce & Business –Kathmandu, Nepal
2008-2010	Tribhuvan University , Bachelor's Degree-Sociology & Population – Bhaktapur, Nepal
2011-2016	Tribhuvan University, Master's Degree-Sociology, Gender & Inequality

TRAINING & CERTIFICATION

- Intercultural communication
- Juvenile Justice Counselor: Certified to State of Utah
- NSC CPR/First Aid Course

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

- Certified Korean language proficient
- Advanced level Hindi
- Native Nepali Speaker

Training & Coaching

2014- Trained USANA customer services employees in Korea 2015-2016 Training to KR managers with various market's need

References

Aaron Grow

Customer Service Manager

Phone: 801-289-6118

E-mail: <u>Aaron.Grow@us.usana.com</u>

Jalene Bassett

Director of International Market Support

Phone: 801-201-8603

E-mail: Jalene.Bassett@us.usana.com

Eric Oldroyd

Director of Compliance & Audit

Phone: 801-954-7849

E-mail: Eric.Oldroyd@us.usana.com